Guide to the Harold Moser Collection on John Agg, 1813-2000s RL.11528
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Harold Moser collection on John Agg
1813-2000s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Moser, Harold D.
RL.11528
1.0 Linear Feet
Harold D. Moser research materials about the life and work of John Agg (1783-1855).
Biographical / Historical
Harold D. Moser (d. 2016) served as editor of the Daniel Webster Papers Project (Dartmouth College) and the Papers of Andrew Jackson (University of Tennessee), and was a professor of American history at the University of Tennessee from 1979 to 2003. He was also a scholar and researcher on John Agg, an affiliate of Daniel Webster.
John Agg was born in Evesham, England on November 29, 1783. He was the oldest of five children born to his father, (also) John Agg, who was a printer and publisher. Agg eventually decided to learn the trade himself. Beginning in 1811, he edited Towntalk, or Living Manners, in London. In 1814, Agg was sentenced imprisoned and fined for libel. After his release, he emigrated to the Washington, D.C. to work as a stenographer and court reporter for Congress. He also served as editor of a daily national journal. Agg died on April 13, 1855, at the age of 71.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Harold Moser Collection on John Agg was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Collection Overview
Research material from various libraries and online searches compiled by Dr. Moser regarding John Agg, including handwriting analyses, biographical and genealogical information, and other secondary source materials. Includes a copy of Agg's 3-volume set The Secret Memoirs of an Illustrious Princess; or, The Royal Sufferer, edited by Agg and printed in London in 1813 by M. Jones, Newgate-Street and G. Hughes, No. 221 Tottenham-Court-Road.
Publishers and publishing -- United States; Periodical editors -- United States; Agg, John, 1783-1855
- Agg papers: library research, undated (Box 1)
- Bibliography, undated (Box 1)
- Business records, Public Records Office research, undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
- General research and notes re: Agg, 1980s-2000s (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes handwritten notes, genealogy and family trees, and other library research printouts.
- Gloucester County NJ deeds, 2006 and undated (Box 1)
- Handwriting analysis, 2005 and undated (Box 2)
  Moser's handwriting analysis of Agg's signature and other words; notes and research regarding him and forgeries.
- Hudson River portfolio, 1989 and undated (Box 2)
- Internet searches and eBooks re: Agg research, 2000s (Box 2)
- John Agg arrival, undated (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous materials, 1990s-2000s (Box 2)
- New Jersey Supreme Court cases, 2006 and undated (Box 2)
- Ocean Harp, undated (Box 2)
- The Secret Memoirs of an Illustrious Princess; The Royal Sufferer, 1813 (Box 2)
  Volume, edited by Agg.
- Photocopy of will of John Agg, Sr. (1832), undated (Box 2)
- Thomas Agg, undated (Box 2)